McKersie, Robert B., Additional Files /4071
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Robert B. McKersie Additional Files
1968-1978
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
McKersie, Robert B.
/4071
4 cubic feet
4 linear ft.
Records (documents).
3085694
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, January 13, 2016
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, February 22, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Robert B. McKersie, DBA
Professor of Management, Emeritus, Sloan School of Management, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
Robert McKersie is professor emeritus of management at the MIT Sloan School of Management, where he has been since 1980. Prior to his time at MIT, he served as dean of the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University, and as a faculty member of the Graduate School of Business at the University of Chicago. McKersie has served on several presidential commissions at the national level, is a member of the National Academy of Arbitrators, and was president of the National Industrial Relations Research Association (now the Labor and Employment Relations Association). He is the author of numerous articles relating to human resources, industrial relations, and operations management.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 4033: Robert B. McKersie Files 4054: ILR School Dean's Office Additional Files 4343: Robert B. McKersie Collections
McKersie, Robert B.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3085694
- Akron, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Arizona (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Alameda County, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Boston, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Buffalo, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Canton (Stark County), 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Charlotte (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Cincinnati, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Cleveland, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Contra Costa County (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Dayton, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Delaware, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Detroit, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Denver, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- El Paso, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Evansville, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Indianapolis, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Fresno, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Kansas City, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Las Vegas, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Little Rock (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Los Angeles, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Marin Multi-County, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Miami, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Monterey County, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Nashville, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- New Bedford, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- New Haven, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- New Orleans, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- New York City, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Omaha, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Pasco Et Al (Southeastern Wash.), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Pittsburgh, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Portland (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Rhode Island, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Rochester, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Sacramento, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- St. Louis, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- San Mateo, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Santa Clara, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Santa Cruz County (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Seattle (King County), 1971 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- South Bend (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Spokane (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Syracuse (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Cases Rewrite (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Atlanta, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Newark, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Philadelphia, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- San Francisco (Box 1, Folder 50)
- St. Louis, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Washington, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Article, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Contemporary (Black) Issues in Labor, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- References, Etc. From IRC, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- News Items to Minority - Part'N Plans from RBM, IRC, etc., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- HT Clippings: City Specific, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Clippings: Phila Plan, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- The Chicago Plan: RBM file borrowed from Carmick (MICH), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Wardlaw OFCC File, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Chicago News Clippings, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Chicago Clippings June/72, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Mills + Northup Papers, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Monograph, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Office of National Projects: Funded NT Copies 9/24/72, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Affirmative Action, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Employment Discrimination and Affirmative Action - Construction Industry, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Bound
- The Negotiations of the Chicago Plan, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- AFL-CIO, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Alemada County (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Boston, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Atlanta, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Buffalo, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Chicago, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Denver, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Dept. of Labor - Manpower Administration, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Dept. of Labor - News Releases, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Detroit, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Human Resources Development Institute, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Indianapolis, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Ithaca, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- New Orleans, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- New York, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- News Clippings, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Notes - Washington Trip - 7-18-74, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- OFCC - Washington, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Manpower - Questionnaire (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Recruitment -and- Training - Program, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Rochester - Visit, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- San Francisco, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Washington, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- The Joint Minorities Development Program, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Evaluation of Apprenticeship Outreach Program (AOP), 1970 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- An Evaluation of the Apprenticeship Outreach Program (AOP), 1970 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Manpower Programs and Black Progress, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Affirmative Action -and- The New York Plan: A Critical Analysis, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Washington, D.C., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- New Applications of Collective Bargaining, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- The University of Chicago (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Hometown Plans in The Construction Industry, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (Box 3, Folder 1)
- McHowrie, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Misc., 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Equal Employment Opportunity, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Equal Employment Opportunity, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- The University of Chicago, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Early McK Results, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- EEOC Research, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Traves, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Growth Research, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Contacts, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- EEOC, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Program Planning - Earnings, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- EEOC, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Michigan Report on Racial Negotiations, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- The Chicago Plan, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- EEO, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Misc., 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Manpower, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Bob Tyson, 1970-1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- The Negotiation of the Chicago Plan, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- C.R. Tyson, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)